Bjørn Christian Weinbach

RESEARCHER · DATA SCIENTIST

Gildevangen 5, 6856 Sogndal, Norway

🛮 (+47) 458 82 126 | 🗷 bcwein343@mail.com | 🖸 bcwein | 🛅 bjørnchristianweinbach | 💆 @bcwein | 🎓 Bjørn Christian Weinbach

"Prediction is very difficult, especially if it's about the future."

Summary.

Current Researcher at The Western Norway Research Institute and Phd Student at Western Noray University of Applied Sciences. BE in Computer Science from The Norwegian University of Science and Technology, Gjøvik. M.Sc. in Computer Science from University of Stavanger. Main area of research is Deep Learning and Object Detection.

Work Experience

Western Norway Research Institute

Sogndal, Norway

SUMMER INTERNSHIP / RESEARCHER / PHD STUDENT

Jun. 2021 - today

- · Research Intern summer of 2021. Participated in Teknoløft Sogn og Fjordane with an aim of identifying data science applications in the region.
- Masters Thesis: Fairness and Interpretability in Machine Learning written together with University of Stavanger and Western Norway Research Institute.
- Full Time employee as of August 2022 working as a researcher in Teknoløft Sogn og Fjordane.
- PhD Student as of January 2023.

Norwegian Digitalisation Agency

Leikanger, Norway

SUMMER INTERNSHIP Jun. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- Tasked with planning and developing a new application aimed at youth in Norway.
- Worked as back-end developer during the internship. Mostly using PHP and the Drupal 8 framework.

Norwegian University of Science and Technology.

Gjøvik, Norway

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Aug. 2018 - Jun. 2020

- Teaching assistant in Fundemental Programming in C++ fall of 2018 and 2019. Worked mainly by supervising and guiding first year students in weekly tasks and during assignments. Also graded assignments and helped students preaparing for exams.
- Teaching assistant in Object-Oriented Programming in C++ sprint of 2019 and 2020. Worked mainly by supervising and guiding first year students in weekly tasks and during assignments. Also graded assignments and helped students preaparing for exams.
- Teaching assistant in Algorithmic Methods in C++ sprint fall of 2019. Worked mainly by supervising and guiding second year students in weekly
 tasks and while preaparing for exams.

Sogn og Fjordane County Municipality

Leikanger, Norway

COMPUTER TECHNICIAN & CUSTOMER SUPPORT

Aug. 2015 - May. 2017

- · Maintenance taks in the windows server environment, customer support and other technical tasks.
- Worked here as an apprentice until january 2017. Employed as Computer Technician from january to may.

Presentation

Presenter at Framtidsfylket in Trondheim

Trondheim, Norway

FRAMTIDSFYLKET - TRONDHEIM

March. 2023

- Introduced The Western Norway Research Institute.
- · Presented myself, my team, department and the Research areas of The Western Norway Research Institute.
- Encouraged students from The Norwegian University of Science and Technology to apply.

Lunch Presentation at the Western Norway University of Applied Sciences

Sogndal, Norway

FAGLUNSJ: BJØRN CHRISTIAN WEINBACH - KUNSTIG INTELLIGENS I AKADEMIA

Feb. 2023

Sep. 2022

- Introduced ChatGPT and Large Language Models.
- Discussed the challenges with Large Language Models and the future developments of the techology.
- Responded to questions about AI technologies and related technologies...

Presenter at Speedforsking at Western Norway University of Applied Sciences

Sogndal, Norway

SPEEDFORSKING

- Introduced the philosophical definitions of Information and Data.
- Presented Images as a valid and valuable data source.
- Discussed the rise of social media and the true value of data.

Organizing Committee

Organiser, SAIDD | Symposium on AI, Data and Digitalization

Sogndal Norway

Education

Western Norway University of Applied Sciences

Sogndal and Bergen, Norway

PHD IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (ONGOING)

• Ongoing PhD in Computer Science. Main area of focus is computer vision and object detection.

University of Stavanger

Stavanger, Norway

M.Sc in Computer Science - Data Science

Aug. 2020 - Jun. 2022

• Engineering degree in Computer Science with specialisation in Data Science.

Uppsala University Uppsala, Sweden

Aug. 2021 - Jan. 2022 **EXCHANGE SEMESTER**

· Elective courses in computer science with specialisation in data science, stochastic machine learning, databases II and image analysis.

Norwegian University of Science and Tecgnology

Gjøvik, Norway

B.E. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Jun. 2017 - Jun. 2020

• Engineering degree in computer science. Elective courses were Mathematics 3, Infrastructure as Code and Introduction to Artificial Intelligence.

Sogn og Fjordane County Municipality

Leikanger, Norway

CERTIFICATE OF APPRENTICESHIP: COMPUTER TECHNICIAN

Aug. 2015 - Jan. 2017

· Apprenticeship at the Sogn og Fjordane County Municipality.

Extracurricular Activity

Red Party - Sogndal Norway

LEADER AND BOARD MEMBER Jan. 2023 - Present

- Established the red party as a local party in Sogndal.
- Elected for 1 year as local party leader
- · Areas of interest include climate change, nature preservation and inequality.

Norwegian Society for the Conservation of Nature

Norway

BOARD MEMBER Mar. 2023 - Present

- · Elected as board member.
- · Work area has been preservation of Sognefjorden and the local nature in the region of Indre Sogn.